mtbdirect.com.au 2019-04-10

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out how Mountain Bikes Direct uses and protects any information that you provide when you use this website.

Mountain Bikes Direct is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. This policy changes from time to time, so if you ever have any concerns you should check this page to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

 **We may collect the following information:**

  * name
  * contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

 **What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to process and fulfill your orders, understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Processing your orders.
  * Improving our products and services.

You will only be contacted for marketing purposes if you sign up to receive our newsletter and marketing communications. Otherwise, all email communication will be limited e.g. to discuss an order, or occasionally to request your assistance in a survey or research exercise.

 **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.  
Mountain Bikes Direct uses a SSL secured payment gateway from Eway and Paypal to ensure that your credit card details are safe. Mountain Bikes Direct staff do not see any card details which you have directly entered into our site.

 **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. 

We use a specific cookie in order to facilitate the use of Google Universal Analytics for users logged-in to the website. If you are a Logged-In User, we may use your user ID in combination with Google Analytics to track and analyse the pages you visit.  We do this only to better understand how you use the site with a view to offering improvements for all users and to tailor our business and marketing activities accordingly, both generally and specifically to you. Google Analytics cookies do not provide us with any personal information. We also use Google Analytics code that allows for display advertising and other advanced features, including but not limited to, remarketing.

These features are used to advertise online; to allow third-party vendors, including Google, to show you advertising across the Internet; to allow the use of first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies together to inform, optimise, and serve ads based on your past visits to our site and to report how ad impressions, uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to the website. Data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests) is also combined with Google Analytics to better understand the needs of our site users

You may opt out of such display advertising at any time by visiting your [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated%20target=) or by installing and running the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/%20target=)

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information. If you have any specific concerns or requests, please contact us at **[help@mtbdirect.com.au](mailto:help@mtbdirect.com.au) ** 

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to us via email.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
